DHR&Hakugetsu Sub
翻譯：モビイ•ディック CRF 因果律 果妹子  後期：水姬、KoU
我が降谷家は
ご覧のとおり　寺である
The Furuya home is,
as you can see, a temple.
このところ
ちょっとした変化があったが
There have been some
slight changes here lately,
変わることなく
家事全般をこなしていくのが
but it is the task of me, Furuya Mero,
to carry on the general
household chores, without changing.
私　降谷萌路の務めである
礼弥　あんま外　出るなよ
Rea, don't stay outside too long!
今日　天気いいほうなんだから
The weather today is pretty nice, after all!
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry.
あッ　萌路ちゃん
Ah... Mero!
あれ？
Huh?
What's with her?
何だアイツ？　って　ほら
中　入って
Come on, come inside!
Mm-hmm...
さて　皆様におかれましては
Now, all of you may be concerned
にーと礼弥殿の先行きも
気になるところであろうが
as to the future outlook
for Brother and Lady Rea,
but I would like to invite
you to join me, Furuya Mero,
今回は　ちょっと箸休め的に
私　降谷萌路のはなしに
for this bit of a palate-cleansing
side dish of a story.
＜おつきあいいただきとう
存じまする＞
Hey, Mero!
お～い　萌路
"Eiro Mero"
Nemurenai yoru ni kiita monogatari ga
What if the story I heard that sleepless night
esoragoto da to shitara
was all just an impossible dream?
Eien wo shiru yori kairaku wo motomete
What if I pursue pleasure, and lament the moment
ima wo kuyande shimau no wa
instead of learning about the eternities
kokoro no fukaku ni sumitsuita kage kara
so that I can escape from the shadows
nigeru tame da to shitara
that dwell deep within my heart?
Sore demo atashi wa atashi wa ai shite irareru nara
But even so, as long as I, as long as I can still keep loving
Hanbun ni wareta taiyou ga asa wo tsurete kite
The sun split in half brings with it the morning
yami ni nareta shinkei wo jiwari shigeki suru
gradually stimulating my nerves, so used to the darkness
Okiwasureta ano ai wa aete sono mama de
I'll dare to leave the love that I'd misplaced as it is
Shinario no kieta monogatari wa
A story whose plot has been erased,
jiyuu ni jiyuu ni kaji wo totte
freely, freely, takes the helm,
motto takaku e maiagatte
soaring ever higher
It's just about time to go.
そろそろ出かけるからな
"A Mother`s... Hand..."
Will you be late today?
今日は
遅くなるのであるか？
Yeah. I'm visiting with
three different parishioners.
ああ　檀家さんを
三つほど回るから
I'll have my supper before I come back.
夜ご飯は済ませてくるよ
あい分かった
Okay, got it.
あと　千紘も礼弥ちゃんと
一緒にいるから　いらないって
Also, Chihiro says he'll be
with Rea, so he won't need to eat.
You don't say.
そうであるか
When Chihiro said he was
accepting responsibility for her,
千紘のヤツ
彼女の責任を取るとかいって
I wasn't sure how it would turn out at first,
最初は
どうなるかと思っていたけど
but he's hanging in
there surprisingly well, huh?
意外と頑張っているよな
Yeah, Brother, of all people.
あの
にーがのう…
He's usually so dependent,
always relying on you for everything.
いつもだらしなくって　何でも
お前に頼り切っていたのになあ
Mm-hmm...
うむ
Now he says he has to protect her.
彼女を守らなきゃ
とか言っちゃって
しっかりしてきたよ　アイツも
He's getting his act together.
はあ？　おい　萌路
Hey, Mero...
There's no point in sweeping the
same spot over and over, is there?
同じところばかり掃いたって
意味ないんじゃないか？
Oh...
うむ…
Well, I'm off.
じゃ　行ってくるよ
Ho...
Yes, like Father said,
そう　父も言っていたが
it's possible that I have never
seen Brother like this before.
このような　にーを
私は初めて見たかもしれない
誰かのために
一生懸命になっている　にーの姿
The way Brother is working as
hard as he can for someone else...
うんば～
"Shiyo Middle School No. 7"
Do Not Enter
ほら　すげえだろ
Come on! Isn't this amazing?!
Zombies in
Japan, too!!!
"Sharp increase in zombie spottings worldwide!"
「世界中で
ゾンビの目撃が急増中」
"What is happening to humanity right now?!"
「人類に今　何が起きているのか！？」
だってよ
Shinoda Ichie
Age: 12
Height: 143 cm
Weight: ??
Calling: Discovering the unknown
私の級友
This is my classmate, Shinoda Ichie.
Oh, there's no such things as zombies.
え～ッ
ゾンビなんていませんよ
Yasaka Miko
Age: 12
Height: 146 cm
Weight: ??
Calling: Hybrid
And this is Yasaka Miko.
こちらが
I mean, if there really were,
だって本当にいたら
they would be on the news
and in the papers by now.
今頃　ニュースや新聞で
取り上げられてるはずじゃ…
御子　だまされてる
Miko, you're being fooled!
The government is covering up information!
政府が情報を
隠蔽してるんだってばよ～！
ネットにも　そう書いてあったし
It says so on the Internet.
But if the zombies are
increasing that rapidly,
でも　ゾンビが
そんなに増えているのなら
we should be seeing
at least some sign of them.
少しくらいは見かけても
よさそうですけどねえ
そこだ！
えッ？
There you go!
There are zombies, and they're close by!
ゾンビはいるんだよ　すぐ近くに
You mean Mero?
萌路ちゃん？
いや　それは近すぎるだろ
No, that's too close.
I don't mean that!
そうじゃなくて　オレが今　ガチで
There's something that I'm really
concerned about right now!
すっげえ
気になってることがあるんだよ
The art teacher, Yamanouchi.
美術の山之内！
山之内先生？
Miss Yamanouchi?
Yes! Yamanouchi!
そう　山之内だよ
Art Room
The other day, I remembered that
こないだ　美術室に
忘れ物したの思い出してさ
I'd forgotten something in the art room,
and when I went to get it...
取りに行ったんだよ
I thought it was odd for there
to be anyone in there at that hour.
こんな時間に
誰かいるって　おかしいぞって
And then...
そうしたら…
There, eat up. That's a good boy.
Is that good? Here, have some more.
さあ　お食べ　いい子ね
おいしい？　はい　おかわり
血の滴る肉を
手づかみにしてたんだぜ
She was holding meat,
dripping with blood, with her bare hands.
And, she was feeding it
to something, but that's not all...
で　何かに食べさせてたんだけど
それだけじゃなく
Mm-hmm. And speaking of Miss
Yamanouchi, I saw something, too.
うむ　山之内先生といえば
私も…
She always comes to work by car...
あの方は　いつも車で
出勤されているのだが
It looked a lot like there was something alive.
あれは　どうも生き物のようで
Whether it was a zombie or not,
it sure was creepy.
ゾンビかどうかは別として
不気味なものであったな
あッ　そういえば
Oh, now that you mention it...
あん？
山之内先生って
Don't you think that Miss Yamanouchi
ここ最近
妙に　やつれたと思いませんか？
has looked unusually haggard lately?
どうしたんだろうなって
思ってたんですけど
I was wondering, what could the matter be?
よし　分かった　山之内は
この世のものじゃないんだよ～！
All right, I've got it!
Yamanouchi is not of this world!
Is that right?
そうなんですか？
ゾンビなんだよ
She's a zombie.
Then, what was taking that meat?
じゃあ
あのエサをもらっていたのは…
A zombie child, you might
call it, or maybe a zombie underling.
ゾンビの子供っていうか
舎弟っていうか
でも　どう考えたって
ゾンビに決まってるってばよ
But any way you think about it,
it's obviously a zombie!
All right, now that we know that,
we're going to find us some proof
よ～し　こうなったら
山之内がゾンビだって証拠
that Yamanouchi is a zombie!
オレ達で見つけようぜ
Who, us?
私達が？
そうだよ
That's right.
オレ達は　ゾンビを突き止める
We are Zombie Scoop Hunters,
out to turn up zombies!
ゾンビ・スクープハンター
なんだから
そうであったのか？
Is that right? We are?
Beats me.
さあ…
There we go.
よいしょ
Sorry to keep you waiting.
待たせて　ごめんね
いっぱい食べさせてあげるからね
I'm going to feed you nice and full now.
Okay, eat as much as you like today.
さあ　今日も好きなだけ食べてね
Oh, this really is a little scary.
やっぱり　ちょっと怖いです
What are you talking about?
何言ってんだよ　ついに
ゾンビを　この目で見れるんだぜ
We're finally going to be able
to see a zombie with our own eyes!
Here it comes...
出てくるぞ
ほ～ら
There you go.
I-Is this alligator your pet, Teacher?
こッ　このワニ
先生のペットなんですか？
That's right.
そうよ　カワイイでしょ？
Adorable, isn't she?
Yes...
But Teacher, why do you
bring your alligator to school?
でも先生　どうして学校に
ワニなんか連れてくるんですか？
Because I worry about her.
心配なのよ　たまに
ペットのワニが逃げ出して→
You know how sometimes pet alligators run off,
and end up being
on the news, right? That's why.
ニュースになったりするでしょ？
それでね…
まあ　でも本当のところは→
Well, but then, the truth is,
it's because I hate to spend even
a moment apart from my little girl.
私が　この子と　ひと時たりとも
離れたくないからなんだけど
So you stick her in a bag,
and hide her in the art room?
それでバッグに入れて
美術室に隠していたのですか？
Yes.
放課後の時間にね
この子に　ご飯をあげるのが
After school hours, giving her food to eat
is the greatest moment of comfort for me!
私にとって
最高の癒やしの時間なの！
Uh-huh...
She is an absolute man-eater.
この子　すっごく肉食系よ
A-Another thing, Teacher...
lately, you've been looking thin, huh?
あッ　あと先生
最近　ちょっと痩せたっすよね
Is there some reason for that?
それは何か　あったんすか？
ウフッ　ああ　それはね
Ah, that's because the liver
I've been preparing for this little girl
この子のご飯に用意したレバーが
あんまり　おいしそうだったから
has been so delicious,
I've ended up eating it along with her.
つい一緒に食べちゃったのよ
そうしたら
おなか壊しちゃって　ウフッ
But by doing so, I've upset my stomach.
I thought I could eat it like liver sashimi,
レバ刺しみたいなものだと
思っていたけど
下手に生肉なんて
食べるものじゃないわね→
but you should not be careless
when eating raw meat, you know?
This last little while, my tummy
has been in an awful, awful state.
もう　ここ最近
おなかが大変で大変で　ウフッ
Excuse me.
失礼
Ichie, is there any new
zombie information today?
一恵ちゃん　今日は何か
ゾンビ情報　ないんですか？
Nope.
いいや
No, huh?
そうですか
You know what?
Something interesting happened to me.
実は　ちょっと
おもしろいことがあったんですよ
ふ～ん
I've got a very sharp nose, you know.
私　すごく鼻がいいじゃないですか
You do?
そうだっけ
So, yesterday, on my way home...
で　昨日の帰りなんですけど
I started smelling this strange
smell coming from somewhere.
どこかから　すっごく
変なニオイがしてきたんです
ほお～
I don't know how to describe it.
何て言えばいいのかな
It was like the smell of a
dead person's body being boiled.
死んだ人の体を
ゆでたニオイとでもいうか…
Just a minute.
ちょっと待った　御子
Miko, have you ever smelled a
dead person's body being boiled before?
お前　人をゆでたニオイなんて
嗅いだことあんのかよ？
Of course not. I was just
imagining what it was like.
もちろん　ないですよ
ただの想像ですよ
Where do you get your imagination,
and where is it leading you?
その想像力　どこから来て
どこに向かってるんだよ
Come on, let's listen to the rest of the story.
まあ　続きを
聞いてみようではないか
Right.
はい　そのニオイが
強くなるほうに歩いて行くと
I walked over to where the smell was the strongest,
ある一軒家に　ぶつかりました
and came up to a single house.
So, I peeked inside. And when I did...
で　中を覗いてみたんです
そしたら…
おいおい　何か
おもしろくなってきたじゃねえか
Hey, now, this is starting
to get interesting, isn't it?!
Then what happened?
して　どうされた？
I kept looking around, of course.
もちろん探り続けました　でも…
But...
Excuse me, there...
ちょっと　あなた
Is there something you need from us?
ウチに何か用？
Somebody help me...!
助けてください
アハハハッ
やんなっちゃうわよ　本当に
Oh, you've got to be kidding! Really!
Imagine, smelling the soup
and seeing the bones in our garbage,
スープのニオイと
ゴミ箱の骨ガラで
and thinking we were zombies!
ウチにゾンビがいると
思っちゃうなんてねえ
I really do have to watch that smell, huh?
やっぱり　ニオイには
注意しないとな　アハハハッ
Um... So what exactly is this?
あの　一体　これはどういう…
My husband has quit his job, you see,
and is starting a ramen shop.
ウチの人がね　会社を辞めて
ラーメン屋を始めるの
Which is why he is working
day and night to come up with
それで　今は
ウチ独自のスープを作ろうと
our own special blend of soup.
日夜
研究しているってわけなのよ
Here.
はい
うッ
Some sort of fate has brought you here,
so by all means, have a taste.
これも何かの縁だから
ぜひ　味見してってよ
I know it must smell strong,
but I'm sure it's delicious.
臭いでしょうけど
きっと　おいしいわよ
Go on, don't be shy.
ほら　遠慮しないで
R-Right...
ぱあッ
After I took one bite, I couldn't stop myself!
一口　食べてみたら
もう止まらなくなっちゃって
From what I heard, it sounds
like it was tonkotsu style, huh?
話を聞くかぎり
豚骨方式であるな
It was the first time I'd ever eaten it.
ああいうの
初めて食べました
ぱあ～ッ
Listen, Miko, what is the
ultimate point of this story?
あのさ　御子　結局これって
どういう話なわけ？
Just that the ramen
was unbelievably delicious.
そのラーメンが
すごく　おいしかったっていう…
It isn't a story about zombies?!
ゾンビの話じゃねえのかよ！
Still, I'm sure the ramen
tastes better than zombies do.
でも　あのラーメンは
きっとゾンビより　おいしいですよ
What kind of comparison is that?!
どういう比較だよ　それは…
Aww... zombies sure are hard to find, aren't they?
あ～あ　やっぱゾンビって
なかなか見つからないもんだな
Still, someday,
I'm sure I'm going to find one!
でも　いつか
絶対　見つけてやるからな～！
う～ん　でも実際は
どうなんでしょうねえ
What are they actually like,
I wonder. Mero, what do you think?
萌路ちゃんは　どう思う？
For starters, there has been a zombie
そもそも　ゾンビなら　先日から
ウチに居候しているのだが…
living at our place for a few days now.
Really?!
ホントに？
何か？
What about it?
マジか！　これから見せてくれよ
Do you mean it?!
Let's go and see it!
Sure. But she might not be home,
and be out somewhere.
ああ　でも外出して
家に　おらぬかもしれんが
Then take a picture that we can use as proof!
じゃあ　証拠写真
撮ってきてくれよ
で　「月刊ムォー」に
投稿しようぜ
We can have it printed in "Weekly Muo"!
There are privacy issues at work here, so...
それはプライバシーの観点から
あまり…
Zombies don't have any privacy issues!
ゾンビに
プライバシーなんてあるかよ
No, I was talking about
matters of privacy with our home.
いや　我が家の
プライバシーでもあるので
お寺も客商売的側面があるのでな
There is the business side
to the temple, after all.
あッ…　てか今　ゾンビが外出って
言ってたけど　大丈夫なのかよ？
Wait, you said the zombie might be out.
Are you sure that's safe?
うん？　まあ
適度な運動が大事なのだそうな
Well, apparently,
some moderate exercise is important.
Hey, now, zombies attack people
and eat their flesh, don't they?
ゾンビってば人間　襲って
肉　食べたりするもんじゃね？
No, she's always eating hydrangea leaves,
いや　いつもアジサイの葉
食べてるから草食ではないかと
so I think she's a vegetarian.
Vegetarian?
草食…
That's a whole different mode
of life from a normal zombie, huh?
何か　普通のゾンビと
えらく生態が違うな
Far from a normal zombie,
she said she wanted to be a normal girl.
普通のゾンビというより
普通の女の子になりたい
ようなことを申しておったが
Okay, I don't know what you mean.
Is this actually a zombie?
いや　意味　分かんないし
それ　ホントにゾンビ？
Brother says she is.
にーが　そう言っておる
にー！？　あの変人兄貴の妄言か
Your brother?!
This is your weirdo older brother's baloney?!
He keeps saying,
"I want to kiss a zombie girl," doesn't he?
ゾンビっ娘と
チュッチュしたいよ～
とか言っちゃってんだろ～
Oh, so then this is all fake, huh?
何だ　じゃあガセなんじゃないの？
Who knows?
さあ
I've got some shopping to do,
so I need to get going.
私は買い物があるので　そろそろ
Mm-hmm.
Geez, I thought we had
a chance to leap to fame here.
チェッ　オレら　一躍　有名になれる
チャンスかと思ったのに
Man, your brother needs to be
brought up a little better.
ま～ったく　あの兄貴とか
もっとちゃんと躾しとくように
母ちゃんに言っときなよ
You should tell your mom.
Oh, Ichie...
あッ　一恵ちゃん
うん？
Mero doesn't have...
萌路ちゃんちは…
ああ　ごめん
Oh... Sorry.
Oh, you don't have to worry about it.
ああ　別に気にせんでよい
Yes... my mother is no longer with us.
そう　我が家には母がいない
She had already passed
away before my earlier memories,
私が物心つく前から
もういなかったので
so I don't really have what you
would call memories of my mother.
ほとんど　母との
思い出といえるものがない
ただ　母について
一つだけ覚えていることがある
There is only a single thing
that I remember about my mother.
Boop.
のう…
And that is...
それは
Oh, dear...
あら　お熱かしら？
Do you have a fever?
Oh, whoops. Would you look at me?
あッ　いけない　私ったら
I can't tell your temperature like this, can I?
これじゃ
温度　分からないわよね
Her hand.
手…
A memory of my mother's
cold hand, wrapped up in bandages.
ひんやりした
包帯まみれの母の手の記憶
How come? I just came to borrow
a zombie DVD, like I always do.
何でよ　いつもみたいに
ゾンビＤＶＤ　借りにきただけでしょ
Then hurry up and take it with you, okay?
だったら
さっさと持ってきゃいいだろ
Yeah, but sometimes, I like
watching DVDs together, you know?
だけどさあ　たまには一緒に
ＤＶＤ　見たりしたいじゃん
Yeah, but not today.
だから今日は…
You know, you've been really inconsiderate lately.
何か最近　そっけないよね
Huh?
はあ！？
別にいいんだけど
That's okay with me, though.
Wanko, you're really acting weird.
わんこ　お前　何か変だぞ
Well I'm not just backing down without a fight.
私だって
まだまだ引き下がらないんだから
Eh?
へッ？
何でもない
Nothing!
Ugh, talking to you just mixes my head up.
う～ん　お前と話してると
頭　混乱してくんだよ
Maybe your head has
gone rotten. Like a zombie!
頭が腐ってんじゃない？
ゾンビみたいに
Oh? You mean it?!
えッ　マジで？
何　喜んでんのよ
What are you so happy for?
I was obviously making a joke.
冗談に決まってんでしょ
だよなあ…
Yeah, right...
Hmph.
Brother's snacks. He's gone
and made yet another strange offering.
にーのヤツ
また変なものを　お供えしおって
Good grief, what could he be thinking?
まったく　何を考えておるのやら
Mm-hmm...
うむ
That's better.
これでよしっと
あッ　萌路ちゃん
ああ
Ah, Mero!
お帰り
Welcome home.
Lady Rea, I have returned.
So, did you need something in the cemetery?
礼弥殿　ただいまです
して　お墓に何か用が？
Mm-mm, nothing in particular.
Furuya just had a guest come over,
ううん　特に用はないけど
降谷君に　お客様が来ていて
so I stepped out for a bit.
それで　ちょっと…
ほう
Oh.
Sometimes, I get concerned...
私　時々　心配になるんだ
Hmm?
That I'm making trouble for
Furuya, and others around me.
降谷君や周りの人達に
迷惑かけちゃってるのかなって
あッ　いや　そのようなことは…
No, it's nothing like that.
あッ　ごめんね　変なこと言って
Oh, I'm sorry! I shouldn't have said anything.
萌路ちゃんこそ　何して…
So Mero, what are you up to?
ああ　お参り？
Ah, visiting someone's grave?
Yes, I am...
お参りです
my mother's.
母の…
あッ
O-Oh. I haven't seen your
mother around, so I was wondering...
そっか　お母さん
見かけないと思っていたけど
So that's why.
そうだったんだ
Mero, I'm so impressed.
萌路ちゃんは　えらいなあ
You take care of all
the household chores, huh?
家事全般　こなしてますよね
Well, I've been doing so since I was a little girl.
まあ　幼少からの務めであるから
私なんて
ずっと過保護に育てられたから
I've always been over-parented growing up,
そうやって　一人で何でもやれる
萌路ちゃんのこと　尊敬しちゃう
so I have a lot of respect for you, Mero,
being able to do everything yourself.
Well, if the guys in my family
had their business together more,
まあ　ウチの男性陣が
もっと　しっかりしてくれれば
it would be easier on me.
私も楽なのだが…
Oh, I know!
あッ　そうだ
じゃあ　私にも　これからは
家事のお手伝いさせてください
Please, let me help you
with your chores from now on.
Huh? No, that wouldn't be right.
えッ？　あッ　いや
それは悪いので
Why not? That's not true.
何で？　そんなことないですよ
Besides, I kind of want to do it.
それに　むしろ
やってみたい感じだし
Okay, Mero? Please?
ねッ　萌路ちゃん　お願いします
あッ…
Okay, Mero?
ねッ　萌路ちゃん
Mm-hmm.
Hooray!
やったあ
Uh-oh, what's the matter?
あれれ　どうしたの？
Why are you keeping your head down like that?
そんなに　うつむいちゃって
Oh, you're beet-red! Do you have a fever?
あッ　顔　真っ赤
お熱ですか？
It's cold!
冷たい！
Oh, whoops. I'm a zombie,
あッ　いけない
私　ゾンビだから　手をつけても
so I can't tell your
temperature with my hand on your head.
これじゃ
温度　分からないんだった
わあ～
Mama!
Mama?
ママ？
いや…
No...
I-I-I mean, nothing!
なッ　何でもですぞ
Eh? Hold on!
えッ　ちょっと…
Mero! You forgot something!
萌路ちゃ～ん　忘れ物！
礼弥殿　面目ないです
Lady Rea, I'm sorry.
There, all done. Let's make supper.
さッ　終わったよ
ご飯　作ろッ
Why did I call her that at that moment?
あの時　なぜ私は
そう呼んでしまったのか…
Still, for some reason, I definitely felt it...
でも　なぜか確実に感じたのです
There's a zombie!
This is a zombie...?
これが　ゾンビ
キレイな人～
She's so pretty.
This is all a put-on, all right.
やっぱガセだろ
これは…
礼弥殿から　母の面影を…
The shadow of my mother, coming from Lady Rea.
The End
Hitotsu dake kanau no nara
If I had just one wish
kimi no te no naka yureru chiisa na hana de itai
I would want to be a small flower, trembling in your hands
Hajimete miru mabushii kono sekai ga
Even if I become separated from you,
kimi to moshi hagureta to shite mo kitto
in this bright world I'm seeing for the first time,
mitsukedashite
I'm sure I'll find you
Mezametara soba ni iru yo
When I wake up, I'll stay beside you
ashita mo
tomorrow as well
Preview
Mero, how come you're so down?
萌路ちゃん
何で　そんなに元気ないの？
Miss Sanka...!
散華さん
はい
Yes?
Take a hint. Take a hint...!
空気　読んで…　空気　読んで！
Huh? O-Oh... Hmm...?
えッ？　ああ…　はい！
Right!
"Strong... Feelings..."
Next time on Sankarea, episode 10:
Ugh, everyone watch mero.
ああ　みんな　見るメロ
Mero, by any chance,
萌路ちゃん　ひょっとして
私や　わんこさんが入ってきたのが
are you not amused that Miss Wanko and I have joined in?
おもしろくないとか？
散華さん！
Miss Sanka...!